Muhammad Shazrin Bin Shoffie

Mobile: +65 9010 5250 Email: mshazrinbs@gmail.com

Websites: linkedin.com/in/muhammad-shazrin, github.com/shazxrin, shazxrin.me

SUMMARY

Recent Computer Science graduate from National University of Singapore. Demonstrated expertise and proficiency in frontend and backend Web Development; with experience in React, in-depth background in Java and its Java Virtual Machine, and professional experience with the Spring ecosystem. My passion extends to cloud technologies such as distributed systems, containerization and orchestration.

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore

Aug 2021 - May 2024

Bachelor of Computing in Computer Science (Distinction)

• Specializations: Multimedia Information Retrieval (NLP/AI)

Ngee Ann Polytechnic

May 2016 - May 2019

Diploma In Information Technology (Merit)

Specializations: Solutions Architect

SKILLS

Frontend Development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Remix, Node.js, Vite, Vitest, Jest, Playwright

Backend Development

Go, Java, Kotlin, Spring Boot, Spring Framework, JUnit, Hibernate, Gradle, Maven, PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ

Cloud

Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Git, GitHub Actions, Grafana, Prometheus, Azure

Data Science/Machine Learning

Python, Numpy, Pandas, SciKit, PyTorch, Hugging Face

WORK EXPERIENCE

BIOTRONIK, Software Engineer

Aug 2024 - Current

Develop microservices using <u>Spring Boot</u>, <u>Hibernate</u> and <u>PostgreSQL</u> and deployed into <u>Azure</u> managed <u>Kubernetes</u> cluster.

Univers, Software Engineer Intern

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Maintained microservices with <u>Spring Boot</u>, <u>Hibernate</u> and <u>PostgreSQL</u> and deployed with <u>Docker</u> and <u>Kubernetes</u>.
- Facilitated development of a new Extract-Transform-Load (ETL) tool with ability to scale in cloud native environment.

CrimsonLogic, Software Engineer Intern

Mar 2018 - Sep 2018

- Maintained full-stack web applications with Spring Framework, Hibernate, MySQL, HTML and JavaScript.
- Ensured bug-free codebase with static analysis and test cases for code coverage, reducing reported bugs.
- Improved existing search feature by writing optimal SQL queries, improving search results speed.

PORTFOLIO

Personal Website, shazxrin.me

• Built a personal website portfolio using React and Remix, deployed on Vercel.

Home Lab Dec 2023 - Present

- Administrate a personal home lab for running personal applications with <u>Linux</u>, and <u>Docker</u>.
- Setup private networking with <u>Tailscale</u> and <u>NextDNS</u>, and reverse proxy for personal applications using <u>Caddy</u>.

Gemu, github.com/shazxrin/gemu

July 2024 - Present

- Developed a personal game library management web application with <u>React</u>, <u>Spring Boot</u>, <u>Java</u>, <u>PostgreSQL</u> and <u>Docker</u>.
- Designed as a microservice architecture to be able to scale in <u>Kubernetes</u> for batch processing external database and pricing information.

Bloom, github.com/shazxrin/bloom

Aug 2023 - Present

Created a personal time and habit tracking web application with <u>React</u>, <u>Spring Boot</u>, <u>Kotlin</u>, <u>PostgreSQL</u> and <u>Docker</u>.